<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: DevBootcamp | Zach Olauson]]></title>
  <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/categories/devbootcamp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-05T07:45:27-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zach Olauson]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[zmolauson@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 4th 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/04/july-4th-2/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-04T19:23:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/04/july-4th-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So because the whole title situation has really been holding me back from blogging I am going to try to just not have a title on all my blogs, if it doesnt work Ill just use the date but Id rather just use nothing, maybe throw the date in the tags.</p>

<p>Also it appears I fixed the twitter queue issue.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 4th]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/04/july-4th/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-04T19:08:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/04/july-4th</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well today is July 4th. Got up at 6:30 and was at DBC at 7 this morning, a hour earlier than I usually am. Feeling pretty tired already but I feel like I have got quite a bit accomplished. Micah, Brett, and I were planning on grilling some steaks tonight but the courtyard at the apartment has been pretty packed today, and last I was at the apartment there was a pretty good sized beer pong game going, so we may just be cooking some steaks on the grill.</p>

<p>We also went to Trader Joes today and got some stuff, Im hoping to not have lunch and dinner out as much, I am really getting sick of that kind of food. I really enjoy trying to places around the city but not every day.</p>

<p>Tomorrow we have another group project day and then on the weekend the cores revolve mostly around Databases which I am really looking forward to. I really cant believe we are only a week from Phase 2.</p>

<p>I already started looking into sinatra, it seems pretty simple. I just need to brush up on my HTML and CSS a bit and then I should be good to take in a massive amount of Javascript and Sinatra. I am kinda of worried about Javascript because all the times I have tried to learn it, it was a real bitch.</p>

<p>Today I started writing my github project landing page, using Sinatra of course, figured I might as well just through myself into it and see what happens.</p>

<p>I attempted to fix the twitter issue, I kept getting the same tweet every deploy which I really dont understand, I emptied my twitter queue after finally figuring out how to empty it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Titles are the hardest part of writing these]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/03/titles-are-the-hardest-part-of-writing-these/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-03T07:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/03/titles-are-the-hardest-part-of-writing-these</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want to try to write a new one of these every morning, and I usually have time. I can never think of a title though, maybe starting tomorrow I will just put the date, or give it a title then remove it before I post, I have to write something when I create the post because thats how its stored date-time-title.md</p>

<p>I slept so good last night except I woke up more tired that I have ever work up since I got here. This post will probably just random thoughts put together in no order or maybe not even appear to be english.</p>

<p>Today we are doing &ldquo;fireside&rdquo; chats on our portfolios and last night I finished up my portfolios so I am feeling pretty good about that.
Also we get to scrape hackernews as a core so that should be pretty awesome, hopefully theres some stuff not about snowden or prism so whatever we scrape isnt stupid.</p>

<p>This morning I figured out my dropbox was constantly synching everyone in my cohorts dropbox folder along with mine so that was destroying my battery life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week 2 Has Begun]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/02/week-2-has-begun/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-02T07:01:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/02/week-2-has-begun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So week one was nuts. Not as extreme of a workload as I expected, but theres always been something to be done. Week 2 is Object Oriented Programming, which I am really looking forward to. Im not super good with classes but I have a pretty good understanding so hopefully I get paired today with someone who can explain it a little more as we work.</p>

<p>Yesterday we did Engineering Empathy, which I didnt hate, but its certainly not part of what I am used to, but I have been trying to get out of my comfort zone while I am here so that certainly did it.</p>

<p>Also yesterday we had Improv night, which was also nuts. That also got me out of my comfort zone. The instructor was very nice and he had us doing cool stuff, I just wasnt into it. I much rather would have been coding for that 3 hours but I get why they have us do it, so thats cool.</p>

<p>I got thinking yesterday about some cool shit I could build in Sinatra, even though I dont know Sinatra, but in my spare time these next two weeks I could probably learn Sinatra.</p>

<p>I would like to explore the idea of building the following:</p>

<p>Cards Against Humanity
Online version of our chatroom</p>

<p>And I had a few more ideas but of course I cant think of them&hellip;</p>

<p>I dont want to spend too much time doing that though because if I have extra time I should be helping others who are having a more difficult time with the material we are covering, not only because I want them to succeed but also it will help me understand the concepts I am trying to explain. Also I want to make sure I have a pretty good understanding before I try to explain something because I would hate to explain something wrong and them think its right from now on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week One & Speaker Night]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/28/week-one-and-speaker-night/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-28T07:48:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/28/week-one-and-speaker-night</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I feel like week one is going really well so far. Today we are tackling Sudoku which I dont currently have any ideas for but we have about a hour until that would be a issue anyways. Yesterday Ryan and I paired and we got a lot of work done and solved some cool problems, which was pretty awesome.</p>

<p>The speaker last night was incredible. Hands down my favorite speaker Ive ever heard. He was funny and he was talking about topics we all cared about, which was awesome. He was the lead ( I think ) for the Mozilla Badges project and really gave me a lot to think about. He never stayed at a single job for more than 2 years, just because the job he was at wouldnt let him try to technologies, or old, that he wanted to play with learn, which is awesome that he just was learning so much.</p>

<p>&mdash;&ndash; Im going to continue this post today (Saturday, didnt get a chance to finish yesterday &mdash;&ndash;</p>

<p>Yesterday was one one of my least favorite days in my recent memory. We did a Sudoku solver as a group and our group dynamic did not work. I was so mentaly, just dead, I left right at 5 and just went to lay down for a bit. I couldnt even think.</p>

<p>Today, I am going to work on the weekend cores, which there isnt a whole lot then I am going to try to work on the chat app that Brett and I built last Sunday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
