<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: DevBootcamp | Zach Olauson]]></title>
  <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/categories/devbootcamp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-03T07:51:42-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zach Olauson]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[zmolauson@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Titles are the hardest part of writing these]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/03/titles-are-the-hardest-part-of-writing-these/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-03T07:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/03/titles-are-the-hardest-part-of-writing-these</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want to try to write a new one of these every morning, and I usually have time. I can never think of a title though, maybe starting tomorrow I will just put the date, or give it a title then remove it before I post, I have to write something when I create the post because thats how its stored date-time-title.md</p>

<p>I slept so good last night except I woke up more tired that I have ever work up since I got here. This post will probably just random thoughts put together in no order or maybe not even appear to be english.</p>

<p>Today we are doing &ldquo;fireside&rdquo; chats on our portfolios and last night I finished up my portfolios so I am feeling pretty good about that.
Also we get to scrape hackernews as a core so that should be pretty awesome, hopefully theres some stuff not about snowden or prism so whatever we scrape isnt stupid.</p>

<p>This morning I figured out my dropbox was constantly synching everyone in my cohorts dropbox folder along with mine so that was destroying my battery life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week 2 Has Begun]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/02/week-2-has-begun/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-02T07:01:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/02/week-2-has-begun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So week one was nuts. Not as extreme of a workload as I expected, but theres always been something to be done. Week 2 is Object Oriented Programming, which I am really looking forward to. Im not super good with classes but I have a pretty good understanding so hopefully I get paired today with someone who can explain it a little more as we work.</p>

<p>Yesterday we did Engineering Empathy, which I didnt hate, but its certainly not part of what I am used to, but I have been trying to get out of my comfort zone while I am here so that certainly did it.</p>

<p>Also yesterday we had Improv night, which was also nuts. That also got me out of my comfort zone. The instructor was very nice and he had us doing cool stuff, I just wasnt into it. I much rather would have been coding for that 3 hours but I get why they have us do it, so thats cool.</p>

<p>I got thinking yesterday about some cool shit I could build in Sinatra, even though I dont know Sinatra, but in my spare time these next two weeks I could probably learn Sinatra.</p>

<p>I would like to explore the idea of building the following:</p>

<p>Cards Against Humanity
Online version of our chatroom</p>

<p>And I had a few more ideas but of course I cant think of them&hellip;</p>

<p>I dont want to spend too much time doing that though because if I have extra time I should be helping others who are having a more difficult time with the material we are covering, not only because I want them to succeed but also it will help me understand the concepts I am trying to explain. Also I want to make sure I have a pretty good understanding before I try to explain something because I would hate to explain something wrong and them think its right from now on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week One & Speaker Night]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/28/week-one-and-speaker-night/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-28T07:48:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/28/week-one-and-speaker-night</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I feel like week one is going really well so far. Today we are tackling Sudoku which I dont currently have any ideas for but we have about a hour until that would be a issue anyways. Yesterday Ryan and I paired and we got a lot of work done and solved some cool problems, which was pretty awesome.</p>

<p>The speaker last night was incredible. Hands down my favorite speaker Ive ever heard. He was funny and he was talking about topics we all cared about, which was awesome. He was the lead ( I think ) for the Mozilla Badges project and really gave me a lot to think about. He never stayed at a single job for more than 2 years, just because the job he was at wouldnt let him try to technologies, or old, that he wanted to play with learn, which is awesome that he just was learning so much.</p>

<p>&mdash;&ndash; Im going to continue this post today (Saturday, didnt get a chance to finish yesterday &mdash;&ndash;</p>

<p>Yesterday was one one of my least favorite days in my recent memory. We did a Sudoku solver as a group and our group dynamic did not work. I was so mentaly, just dead, I left right at 5 and just went to lay down for a bit. I couldnt even think.</p>

<p>Today, I am going to work on the weekend cores, which there isnt a whole lot then I am going to try to work on the chat app that Brett and I built last Sunday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 2: Pair Programming, Mentors, and Badassery]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/25/day-2-pair-programming-slash/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-25T21:24:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/25/day-2-pair-programming-slash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was my second day at DevBootcamp in Chicago. It was simply awesome.</p>

<h4>Pairing</h4>

<p>We paired with the same person all day today and my pair ended up being Brett, and the pair programming experience was really good. I just kept my hands away from the keyboard and mouse while navigating so I wouldnt accidently take control when my brain started going, and when I did take over, I asked first so I wasnt stepping on any toes.</p>

<h4>Mentors</h4>

<p>We met our mentors tonight, my mentor is Rob Lambert, who is a java developer. I&rsquo;m not sure what mentors provide to us, but its cool that people are willing to give up some of their day to help us beginners out.</p>

<h4>A Bit of Badassery</h4>

<p>Today was pretty badass, since Brett and I were pretty productive we had a bit of extra time so I helped some people out, which was really cool to be able to help others instead of only asking for help, which we also had to do because regular expressions are crazy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Few Thoughts on Pair Programming]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/24/a-few-thoughts-on-pair-programming/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-24T21:52:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/24/a-few-thoughts-on-pair-programming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So.. Pair Programming.</p>

<p>Today was my first real shot at it. Im not sure what to think of it, but I am sure that if we are learning how to do it properly, its good.
I thought it was pretty good, at some points and it was mostly dependant on who I was pairing with. Some people it really was pretty good, but then a couple it was just eh, and I dont blame anyone but myself.</p>

<p>I am so used to working on my own and in my own little zone, when I see a possibility of improving the code or something I just jump on the keyboard and starting layin down code. Which certainly isnt how pair programming works.</p>

<p>Ill keep posting on pair programming as I get better / or worse at it. I would really like to get really understand, sooner than later, so I dont hurt my partners learning while pairing, but for now we are all new to it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
