<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: DevBootcamp, | Zach Olauson]]></title>
  <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/categories/devbootcamp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-06T22:00:27-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zach Olauson]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[zmolauson@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Few Things About DBC Chicago]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/06/a-few-things-about-dbc-chicago/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-06T21:40:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/06/a-few-things-about-dbc-chicago</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I first started this blog I wanted to write a bit about the Chicago DBC as a whole, because when I got accepted they hadnt even opened their doors for the Squirrels yet ( first cohort ). So unlike the DBC in San Francisco you couldnt look up anything you wanted about the place and have a ton of sources of info. So I kinda wanted to do that for DBC Chicago, even though no one reads this, maybe someone looking for answers will find it, and it will be helpful.</p>

<h4>Food &amp;&amp; Drink</h4>

<p>A lot of people go out to eat at lunch, you have a hour and a half.During Week 1 I ate out almost every day for lunch and dinner and was feeling pretty shitty so now I am trying to bring food or go back to my apartment and eat but its cool to try to places. There is a fridge for boots and each boot has a box for other food.</p>

<p>Merchandise Mart is just across the street, and they have a pretty good selection of things.</p>

<p>There is 2 Subways within a block and beyond that there is quite a large selection.</p>

<p>In the Kitchen at DBC there is 2 coffee makers, 1 of which is a Keurig, so bring your cup things if you want that, I havent used either but there is almost always coffee available, before 3 I think.</p>

<p>There is also a Starbucks in the main floor of the building and a CVS right across the street for other drinks or snacks.</p>

<p>Also theres a bar / burger place on the main floor but the 1 time I went there because I wanted a burger they were out of burgers, so I no longer will go there.</p>

<h4>Apartments / Housing</h4>

<p>I was really lucky and ended up getting a apartment a block away from DBC with a fellow Grasshopper, and honestly, its awesome. Its not overly expensive and the convience of living so close is worth any extra to me. Also Trader Joes and Whole Foods arent that far away which is pretty nice for groceries.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.rivernorthpark.com/">http://www.rivernorthpark.com/</a></p>

<p>Besides that I guess I would just check for sublets on craigslist or something, I think some other guys are trying to get a list together of places near by so I will link to that in the future if it happens.</p>

<h4>Hours?</h4>

<p>The core hours are 8 to 5 ( you check in with your group at 7:45 ) after that you are free to leave but its a great work enviroment, everyone is super helpful, and you will have stuff to do.</p>

<p>I usually get there at about 7:30ish and leave around 10ish sometimes later, depending if I have to get groceries or do laundry.</p>

<p>Weekends are optional but you still have work to do so if you dont come in you will still have to put in some good hours of work. Weekends get a little louder than core hours during the week so I suggest headphones if you need the quiet.</p>

<h4>Work Enviroment</h4>

<p>This is my favorite part about DBC, its a great place to work and everyone is amazing. I have never felt so excited to go somewhere at 7:30 in the morning. Its pretty cool to think that, at any given minute in that place, someone is making something awesome.</p>

<p>Originally I kinda figured it would be wierd, being the n00bs in phase 1 but everyone has been there and everyone is super helpful.</p>

<hr />

<p>If anyone has any questions you can feel free to email me @ <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#x6f;&#58;&#122;&#x6d;&#111;&#108;&#x61;&#117;&#x73;&#x6f;&#x6e;&#x40;&#x67;&#109;&#x61;&#x69;&#108;&#x2e;&#x63;&#x6f;&#x6d;">&#122;&#109;&#x6f;&#108;&#x61;&#x75;&#115;&#x6f;&#x6e;&#64;&#x67;&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#108;&#x2e;&#x63;&#111;&#109;</a> and in my INCREDIBLE AMOUNT OF FREE TIME I will get back to you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
