<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: DevBootcamp | Zach Olauson]]></title>
  <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/categories/devbootcamp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-24T21:48:22-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zach Olauson]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[zmolauson@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Day at DevBootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/24/first-day-at-devbootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-24T21:33:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/24/first-day-at-devbootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So today was my first day at DevBootcamp Chicago. I am not sure how to describe it, so Ill just use a single word: Badass. Everyone is super nice and so pumped to be here, its nuts.</p>

<p>This morning our group was welcomed by a man with a pretty cool mustache in short jean shorts and a guy in strobing sun glasses. It threw me off a bit.</p>

<p>Then when we walked into the front door, we walked through a tunnel of screaming people, one of the more terrifying moments of my life.</p>

<p>Most of the morning consisted of talks about what we will be doing and different stuff while we are here.</p>

<p>We did get to start a bit of coding today, which was fun, we got to do pair programming, which I am not so sure on, I will make a seperate post including my thoughts and whatnot on that as a beginner after I send this one out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only ~30 Minutes Away]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/24/only-%7E30-minutes-away/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-24T07:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/24/only-~30-minutes-away</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well we are only about 30 minutes away from starting. I am not sure what to say, just I am excited and nervous and I cant wait to start diving into some code.</p>

<p>I am not sure if blogging counts as social networking while I am there, so I may just have to write a post tonight about all that I have learned.</p>

<p>As I get more used to the place I want to write about the experience at the Chicago office, because when I applied it hadnt even opened and I havent been able to find much info about it, where as the San Francisco office, you can pretty much find out whatever you want to know from a blog post or two.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tomorrows The Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/24/tomorrows-the-day/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-24T00:17:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/24/tomorrows-the-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So tomorrow&rsquo;s the day that will be the beginning of my time at DevBootcamp. I&rsquo;m so excited and nervous at the same time I am not sure what to even say about it.  I went to dinner tonight with ~10 of the people in my cohort (The Grasshoppers) which was fun.</p>

<p>Also today, which I am pretty proud of / excited about, Brett and I made a chat client created in Ruby using a service called PubNub for instant updating. Its coming a long pretty nicely, and we only have a few hours into which is unbelievable to me. We havent really been pair programming because we have been using both our computers but working a long side each other, which has really sped up everything we have been working on so far. We also uploaded it to github and we are going to give version control a try, instead of just sharing gists to keep each other on the same path.</p>

<p>You can check that out here :
<a href="https://github.com/zacholauson/pubnub_chatroom">https://github.com/zacholauson/pubnub_chatroom</a></p>

<p>Here is his github page:
<a href="https://github.com/brettsanders">https://github.com/brettsanders</a></p>

<p>We have to be there at 7:50 and the doors open at 8, we got a email from Dave (Dave Hoover) on Saturday letting us know what to do, and it really didnt answer a whole lot, which I know it wasnt supposed to.</p>

<p>Anyways, as I was told to, to my family &amp;&amp; friends:</p>

<p>  &ldquo;I am moving to Nepal to find inner peace.
   I like a few of you. That is all.</p>

<p>   &mdash; Zach Olauson"</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
