<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title><![CDATA[Zach Olauson]]></title>
	<link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/"/>
	<updated>2013-06-20T22:54:57-05:00</updated>
	<id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/</id>
	<author>
		<name><![CDATA[Zach Olauson]]></name>
		<email><![CDATA[zmolauson@gmail.com]]></email>
	</author>
	<generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[~4 Days Out]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/20/%7E4-days-out/"/>
		<updated>2013-06-20T15:33:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/20/~4-days-out</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>My DevBootcamp experience starts in just over 4 days, and I am getting pretty nervous. I feel like I am ready but I really dont know. I am going to the DBC office tonight for speaker night, which should be awesome as usual. Ive been reading a book called Creating Command Line Applications in Ruby ( I think thats right ) which has been pretty cool, Im not sure how useful it will be but Ive been just reading it along Well Grounded Rubyist which I am sure will be useful because Ive heard people mention how good it is.</p>

<p>Ive also been struggling with internet in the apartment, I bought a ClearWire hotspot last week when I moved here and at some times its awesome but usually its not, which is my biggest problem with it, if it was always shitty that would be fine I guess because I just need it for downloading files and reading but sometimes its really good. When its really good I get the smart idea to stream some music or a movie while I am working then it takes a shit again and it just pisses me off. I decided to just tether off my phone, its not real fast but its consistant. So last night I call up ClearWire to cancel and some &ldquo;internet expert&rdquo; attempts to fix it, then blames the inconsistant internet on me not shutting down the hotspot. How am I supposed to use the internet if its shut down? The greatest thing during the whole conversation is when I learned that I&rsquo;ve used over 40GB of data in just over a week, I was quite impressed seeing how I hadnt downloaded anything significant, just a few ebooks. Pretty nuts.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby Hack Night Last Night, DBC Speaker Tonight]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/13/ruby-hack-night-dbc-speaker-tonight/"/>
		<updated>2013-06-13T15:01:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/13/ruby-hack-night-dbc-speaker-tonight</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Last night I went to Ruby Hack Night, which was hosted by Enova, with Micah and Priya from DBC, it was pretty awesome. I got to try out Pair Programming, which I still dont fully get but it was pretty cool. We built a JSON oranizer, my partner knew much more than me and proposed we do it with RSPEC which turned out pretty cool. I had only used RSPEC one other time and it was during the Hartl tutorial, but I really didnt understand it too well. I think I get it a little more now.</p>

<p>Tonight I am going to DBC for the Thursday Speaker Night, the speaker is Eric Lunt who is the CTO of BrightTag, which Im not entirely sure what it does but Im sure Ill understand more after tonight.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Coding in Chicago]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/11/coding-in-chicago/"/>
		<updated>2013-06-11T14:50:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/11/coding-in-chicago</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Got moved into my apartment in Chicago, and have been coding as much as possible. Micah, from my DBC cohort, lives in the same building so I have been working with him a bit.
I also went to Coding Coffee, which was pretty cool, got a bit done on my Imgur / Reddit scraper, and had some shitty Starbucks coffee.
Its been really hot here, which I dont mind so much but its also been extremely humid, which I really dont like, luckily the apartment has really good AC.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Got Some Advice From Phase 4]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/07/got-some-advice-from-phase-4/"/>
		<updated>2013-06-07T22:51:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/07/got-some-advice-from-phase-4</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<h3>Today I talked to Stephen Nguyen, who is in Phase 4 at DBC. He was doing a Google Hangout where anyone could come in and ask questions or just hangout.</h3>

<h3>Heres his blog if you wish to check it out <a href="http://binaryskipper.tumblr.com/">http://binaryskipper.tumblr.com/</a></h3>

<p>So I didnt go in with any specific questions, just thought I would hangout and hopefully chat about code. He gave me some pretty cool info about some plugins for Sublime, such as Bracket Highlighter, Emmet, and SublimeLinter, which all can be found in Package Control.</p>

<p>He also gave me some tips on getting even more prepared for DBC. He said there were some books I should probably check out like &ldquo;Eloquent Ruby&rdquo; (which I have been reading and its awesome), &ldquo;Practical Object Oriented Design in Ruby&rdquo;, &ldquo;Sinatra Up and Running&rdquo;. He also said that doing the exercises in Chris Pine&rsquo;s &ldquo;Learn to Program&rdquo; was very important, he said many people just read through the book and didnt really get all they could take away from the book, he said a lot of the Exercises are similar or the same as their Week 1 challenges, which I am not sure if SF and Chicagos exercises are the same but still good info.</p>

<p>Also he recommended to play around with SQL tables, and play around with Sinatra and Rails, although we wont need Rails until Phase 3 but it would be good to be somewhat familiar.</p>

<p>Overall I&rsquo;m thankful he took the time out of his day to do this for the DBC community, he gave me a lot of helpful tips and I feel a little bit better about were I am in prep.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Got My Computer Back]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/04/got-my-computer-back/"/>
		<updated>2013-06-04T23:52:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/04/got-my-computer-back</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<h3>Going to try to use Markdown a little better from now on, lets see how it goes.</h3>

<p>Today I got back my MacBook (lost my github sticker D: if I can get markdown to work Ill include a image of its badassery) so I can get back to work on Ruby, I probably watched a solid 4 hours of tutorials on Youtube today, hopefully it helped some.</p>

<p>Also I sent off my lease paperwork so hopefully that can get wrapped up in the next couple of days. I also went and bought some things for our apartment, because its unfurnished. Anyways hopefully I learned a bit about markdown so this post doesnt look terrible.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/onYMPGx.jpg" alt="Github Macbook Decal" /></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning as Much as Possible]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/02/learning-as-much-as-possible/"/>
		<updated>2013-06-02T17:14:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/06/02/learning-as-much-as-possible</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Ive just finished up the Chris Pine book and now I&rsquo;m working my way though Eloquent Ruby, trying to get as much work done as possible, because I am taking my laptop in tomorrow to get the screen replaced. So I will be without my machine that I do all my Ruby on for roughly 2 days, but I guess it will give me time to pack and finish up all I need to do before moving.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Assessment]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/05/30/assessment/"/>
		<updated>2013-05-30T21:53:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/05/30/assessment</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>I heard back about my assessment yesterday, overall seemed pretty good, I had some code to refactor which I think I got done pretty well, I want work on one method a bit more I think it could be better.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating Blog]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/05/28/migrating-blog/"/>
		<updated>2013-05-28T16:43:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/05/28/migrating-blog</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>I decided to give Octopress a shot so I am going to migrate from Tumblr to here for the time being, Tumblr is easier but this is much more badass.</p>

<p>Heres my Tumblr if you care to see my previous blogging (which is not extensive at all).
<a href="http://olauson.tumblr.com/">http://olauson.tumblr.com/</a></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
</feed>
