<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Phase1 | Zach Olauson]]></title>
  <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/categories/phase1/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-06T22:06:12-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zach Olauson]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[zmolauson@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Few Things About DBC Chicago]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/06/a-few-things-about-dbc-chicago/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-06T21:40:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/06/a-few-things-about-dbc-chicago</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I first started this blog I wanted to write a bit about the Chicago DBC as a whole, because when I got accepted they hadnt even opened their doors for the Squirrels yet ( first cohort ). So unlike the DBC in San Francisco you couldnt look up anything you wanted about the place and have a ton of sources of info. So I kinda wanted to do that for DBC Chicago, even though no one reads this, maybe someone looking for answers will find it, and it will be helpful.</p>

<h4>Food &amp;&amp; Drink</h4>

<p>A lot of people go out to eat at lunch, you have a hour and a half.During Week 1 I ate out almost every day for lunch and dinner and was feeling pretty shitty so now I am trying to bring food or go back to my apartment and eat but its cool to try to places. There is a fridge for boots and each boot has a box for other food.</p>

<p>Merchandise Mart is just across the street, and they have a pretty good selection of things.</p>

<p>There is 2 Subways within a block and beyond that there is quite a large selection.</p>

<p>In the Kitchen at DBC there is 2 coffee makers, 1 of which is a Keurig, so bring your cup things if you want that, I havent used either but there is almost always coffee available, before 3 I think.</p>

<p>There is also a Starbucks in the main floor of the building and a CVS right across the street for other drinks or snacks.</p>

<p>Also theres a bar / burger place on the main floor but the 1 time I went there because I wanted a burger they were out of burgers, so I no longer will go there.</p>

<h4>Apartments / Housing</h4>

<p>I was really lucky and ended up getting a apartment a block away from DBC with a fellow Grasshopper, and honestly, its awesome. Its not overly expensive and the convience of living so close is worth any extra to me. Also Trader Joes and Whole Foods arent that far away which is pretty nice for groceries.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.rivernorthpark.com/">http://www.rivernorthpark.com/</a></p>

<p>Besides that I guess I would just check for sublets on craigslist or something, I think some other guys are trying to get a list together of places near by so I will link to that in the future if it happens.</p>

<h4>Hours?</h4>

<p>The core hours are 8 to 5 ( you check in with your group at 7:45 ) after that you are free to leave but its a great work enviroment, everyone is super helpful, and you will have stuff to do.</p>

<p>I usually get there at about 7:30ish and leave around 10ish sometimes later, depending if I have to get groceries or do laundry.</p>

<p>Weekends are optional but you still have work to do so if you dont come in you will still have to put in some good hours of work. Weekends get a little louder than core hours during the week so I suggest headphones if you need the quiet.</p>

<h4>Work Enviroment</h4>

<p>This is my favorite part about DBC, its a great place to work and everyone is amazing. I have never felt so excited to go somewhere at 7:30 in the morning. Its pretty cool to think that, at any given minute in that place, someone is making something awesome.</p>

<p>Originally I kinda figured it would be wierd, being the n00bs in phase 1 but everyone has been there and everyone is super helpful.</p>

<hr />

<p>If anyone has any questions you can feel free to email me @ <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#105;&#x6c;&#116;&#111;&#x3a;&#x7a;&#109;&#111;&#x6c;&#x61;&#117;&#115;&#111;&#110;&#64;&#x67;&#109;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;">&#x7a;&#x6d;&#111;&#x6c;&#x61;&#x75;&#115;&#x6f;&#x6e;&#64;&#x67;&#109;&#97;&#x69;&#108;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#x6d;</a> and in my INCREDIBLE AMOUNT OF FREE TIME I will get back to you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ ]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/06/july6/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-06T21:33:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/06/july6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well it appears I finally figured out how to get my posts to not have a title.</p>

<p>I just have to rake new post with a title ( currently using the date ) and then just replaces the title with a space, you have to leave the title tag and put a space otherwise it defaults to your file name.</p>

<p>We are only about a week away from Phase 2, I am feeling really good about Phase 1 but I wont know until Thursday. Alyssa said that if they havent mentioned to us that we are in danger of &ldquo;failing&rdquo; then we are all good, but I guess I like to worry.</p>

<p>When I first started this blog I wanted to write a bit about the Chicago DBC as a whole, because when I got accepted they hadnt even opened their doors for the Squirrels yet ( first cohort ). So unlike the DBC in San Francisco you couldnt look up anything you wanted about the place and have a ton of sources of info. So I kinda wanted to do that for DBC Chicago, even though no one reads this, maybe someone looking for answers will find it helpful. The next post will be that and if someone does find this and needs more answers, you can email me.</p>

<p><a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#x7a;&#109;&#x6f;&#108;&#x61;&#117;&#x73;&#x6f;&#110;&#64;&#x67;&#109;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#x6d;">&#122;&#x6d;&#x6f;&#x6c;&#x61;&#117;&#115;&#x6f;&#110;&#x40;&#x67;&#109;&#97;&#x69;&#108;&#46;&#99;&#111;&#x6d;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ ]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/05/july-5th/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-05T07:46:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/05/july-5th</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Im so exhausted today, luckily the flash cards exercise for today doesnt seem too complex, and I think its a group project so that will be cool.</p>

<p>Im really hoping we dont get stuck in a super boring lecture today, I really wish they could be optional, I dont like wasteing time when only a few people cant get it.</p>

<p>Also testing another no title post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 4th 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/04/july-4th-2/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-04T19:23:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/04/july-4th-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So because the whole title situation has really been holding me back from blogging I am going to try to just not have a title on all my blogs, if it doesnt work Ill just use the date but Id rather just use nothing, maybe throw the date in the tags.</p>

<p>Also it appears I fixed the twitter queue issue.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 4th]]></title>
    <link href="http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/04/july-4th/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-04T19:08:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zacholauson.github.io/blog/blog/2013/07/04/july-4th</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well today is July 4th. Got up at 6:30 and was at DBC at 7 this morning, a hour earlier than I usually am. Feeling pretty tired already but I feel like I have got quite a bit accomplished. Micah, Brett, and I were planning on grilling some steaks tonight but the courtyard at the apartment has been pretty packed today, and last I was at the apartment there was a pretty good sized beer pong game going, so we may just be cooking some steaks on the grill.</p>

<p>We also went to Trader Joes today and got some stuff, Im hoping to not have lunch and dinner out as much, I am really getting sick of that kind of food. I really enjoy trying to places around the city but not every day.</p>

<p>Tomorrow we have another group project day and then on the weekend the cores revolve mostly around Databases which I am really looking forward to. I really cant believe we are only a week from Phase 2.</p>

<p>I already started looking into sinatra, it seems pretty simple. I just need to brush up on my HTML and CSS a bit and then I should be good to take in a massive amount of Javascript and Sinatra. I am kinda of worried about Javascript because all the times I have tried to learn it, it was a real bitch.</p>

<p>Today I started writing my github project landing page, using Sinatra of course, figured I might as well just through myself into it and see what happens.</p>

<p>I attempted to fix the twitter issue, I kept getting the same tweet every deploy which I really dont understand, I emptied my twitter queue after finally figuring out how to empty it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
